Brad Bieselin

Wantagh, NY | 516-557-8407 | <u>brad@bradbieselin.com</u> <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>GitHub</u> | <u>Blog</u> | <u>Portfolio</u>

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full Stack Software Engineer with experience using **frontend and backend technologies** such as React, JavaScript, Ruby, and Rails. Strong skills in application design, testing, and implementation that helps software and technology companies. Computer Science graduate with industry experience in both professional and educational environments.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

React, JavaScript, Ruby, Rails, ActiveRecord, REST APIs, PostgreSQL, AWS, OAuth, Git, SEO, Pair Programming, Agile Development, Test-Driven Development, Heroku, Firebase, Data Structures, OOP, HTML, CSS, Visual Studio

Experience

Witbe Inc New York, NY

Customer Success Manager

06/2021 - 04/2022

- Led and managed 9 projects for customers including Verizon, ViacomCBS, and Peacock by automating VoD asset testing, Channel Change testing, and video/audio quality analysis
- **Prepared** and **facilitated** 8+ hour **interactive training** sessions for customers, including 10+ senior executives on delivery of new products and software which reinforced customer relations

Apple Remote

Software Quality Engineer (Apple Online Store)

02/2021 - 06/2021

- Automated test cases in Java using **Jackson**, **Jenkins**, **TestNG** and **Gradle** which assessed over 3000 scenarios, and advised software engineers of code improvement opportunities
- Achieved fluency in AWS with 40+ hours of training and obtained AWS Cloud Practitioner Certification, and presented a project which demonstrated using AWS for the backend

Technical Projects

DropDesk - GitHub | Live

Ticket system with drag and drop functionality to easily reorganize ticket sorting over 5 categories

- Prepared and developed a full stack application using the frameworks React.js and Ruby on Rails over 3 weeks
- Incorporated the React-Beautiful-DnD library to create a functional drag and drop feature between 5 categories
- Created a full CRUD API using ActiveRecord and a PostgreSQL relational database with 150+ entries
- Designed the custom CSS of the application using styled-components for 12 different components

Spats - Github | Demo

Spotify stats tracker where users can see the top 50 artists and tracks for the last 6 months and for all-time

- Built a full stack project with two peers at Flatiron School using React.js and Ruby on Rails
- Integrated the Spotify Web API to authenticate user login and gather 150+ data points
- Associated data in the Rails API to compare prior user data to current user data and display 50 recommended songs
- Spearheaded and composed the application design using 50+ custom CSS classes

Taskier - GitHub | Live

Task management app that allows users to manage any number of tasks and due dates

- Partnered with one peer and coordinated, programmed, and revamped a React.js and Ruby on Rails application
- Built a full CRUD API with ActiveRecord and Sinatra to incorporate all 4 REST API operations
- Implemented dark mode and designed the website using styled-components and React Hooks
- Leveraged the **ORM** for **SQL** gueries and all 4 database migrations

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Remote

15-Week Full Stack Software Engineering program, focused on Ruby on rails and React.js stack

04/2022 - 07/2022

University at Albany, SUNY
Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Albany, NY 05/2015 - 12/2019